hey folks I'm sitting here by the shore
of Hart Lake which is in the mountains
across a small Valley from Mount Shasta
I thought I would take this opportunity
to talk about what I call my first
principle of science as a scientist
who's interested in human dynamics and
the way civilization functions it's
quite frequent that I come up against
questions that have a political
dimension and so I've done a lot of
thinking about how one science and
politics interact what I've come up with
is a two-part principle the first part
is that it is very natural for a
scientist to have a political
perspective that arises out of what they
come to understand through study so if I
was a climate scientist and I came to
understand that the climate was changing
rapidly as a result of human activity we
would be very natural for me to favor
policies and candidates that took an
aggressive stance with respect to
addressing climate change the second
part of the principle is that it is
completely unacceptable for one's
political perspective to affect what one
comes to believe scientifically the fact
is things are what they are
irrespective of what we want to be true
and science has to be about discovering
what is true irrespective of one's
biases and expectations so the principle
suggests a one-way relationship between
scientific study and political
perspective that one-way relationship
cannot be violated and if one sticks to
this one has no problem navigating the
border between a scientific perspective
and a political one I hope this has been
useful and I look forward to doing the
next video